<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</title>
    <link>https://arshovon.com/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 03:03:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://arshovon.com/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Run a Python script inside a virtual environment in the background</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/python-background/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 03:03:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/python-background/</guid>
      <description>Scenario Suppose, we have a Python script that uses some Python packages. We will use a virtual environment (venv) to install the dependencies. Let&#39;s assume, the script requires a long time to finish. We might need to check the partial output (e.g. some debugging values) from the script before completing the script. We also want to run the script in the background without blocking a terminal window.
I will mock this scenario and will show how to run the Python script inside a virtual environment in the background that writes partial output to a file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorting a list (Python 3)</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/sorting-a-list-python3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 07:01:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/sorting-a-list-python3/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of sorting algorithms such as Bubble sort, Insertion sort, Merge sort, Counting sort, etc. But most of the time, we use builtin sorting function to sort an iterable (e.g. list, tuple, dictionary, custom class with iterator etc.).
Today we will sort a given list of strings in several ways to understand the Python 3 built-in sorted function .
Dataset We will use the 50 U.S. states as our dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>