<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ubuntu on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</title>
    <link>https://arshovon.com/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ubuntu on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 15:05:42 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://arshovon.com/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Avro Phonetic in Ubuntu 20.04 LTS</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-avro-ubuntu-20-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 15:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-avro-ubuntu-20-04/</guid>
      <description>How to install Avro Phonetic in Ubuntu 20.04 LTS  Open Ubuntu Software Search Avro Phonetic in Ubuntu Software  Click Install  Restart the machine or logout and then login again Open Settings &amp;gt; Region &amp;amp; Language  Click on the + (plus) icon in Input Sources Search for Bangla and then click on Bangla (Avro Phonetic)  The Avro Phonetic will be added to the Input Sources  Now you will get a dropdown for selecting bn for Bangla language in top bar right corner You can switch between different Input Source using win + space keyboard shortcut   References  Stackoverflow answer: How to install Avro Phonetic in Ubuntu 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use SSH to logging into Raspberry Pi without Password</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/logging-to-raspberry-pi-without-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 08:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/logging-to-raspberry-pi-without-password/</guid>
      <description>Scenario We can login into remote Raspberry Pi using ssh command:
ssh -p PORT USER@IP password: RASPBERRY_PASSWORD  As it can be seen, we require to input the Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s password each time to establish SSH connection.
Solution: Add local machine&amp;rsquo;s SSH key to Raspberry Pi for password less SSH connection To resolve the scenario, we need to add our local machine&amp;rsquo;s SSH key to the Raspberry Pi.
 Check if you have SSH key in local machine using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Docker Compose on Ubuntu 18.04</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-compose-on-ubuntu-18-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 09:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-compose-on-ubuntu-18-04/</guid>
      <description>What is Docker Compose? Compose is a tool for defining and running complex applications with Docker. With Compose, you define a multi-container application in a single file, then spin your application up in a single command which does everything that needs to be done to get it running.
Compose uses a YML\YAML file to configure application&amp;rsquo;s services. Then, with a single command, all the services can be started or stopped from the configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Docker on Ubuntu 18.04</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-ubuntu-18-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 07:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-ubuntu-18-04/</guid>
      <description>Why Docker? Docker is a tool for running application in an isolated environment.
Some reasons you might want to use Docker:
  Same environment:  Same environment in developers machines and production servers. Acts the same.  Sandbox projects:  Eliminates the risk of getting conflicts while working on different projects on same machine.  Easy working without setup hassle:  Start working directly on others projects without setting all of the environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Java Program in Ubuntu 18.04</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/run-java-program-ubuntu-18-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 15:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/run-java-program-ubuntu-18-04/</guid>
      <description>Run Java Program in Ubuntu 18.04. The program will be run using Oracle&#39;s OpenJDK JDK 8.
 Check if Java Runtime Environment(JRE) is installed in machine:
java -version  If JRE is installed it will show the version information similar to following:
openjdk 11.0.5 2019-10-15 OpenJDK Runtime Environment (build 11.0.5+10-post-Ubuntu-0ubuntu1.118.04) OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM (build 11.0.5+10-post-Ubuntu-0ubuntu1.118.04, mixed mode)  If you do not have installed JRE, install JRE using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install CLI Tools Ubuntu 18.04</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-cli-tools-ubuntu-18-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 15:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-cli-tools-ubuntu-18-04/</guid>
      <description>Install basic development CLI tools in Ubuntu 18.04. It includes:
 oh-my-zsh idle venv git tree  Install Git in Ubuntu 18.04 LTS  Install Git:
sudo apt install git  Add global configuration for Git user:
git config --global user.email &amp;quot;you@example.com&amp;quot; git config --global user.name &amp;quot;Your Name&amp;quot;  Add SSH. Details can be found in this gist
  Install Oh My Zsh in Ubuntu 18.04 LTS  Install Zsh:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>