<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GPGPU on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</title><link>https://arshovon.com/categories/gpgpu/</link><description>Recent content in GPGPU on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 07:05:42 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arshovon.com/categories/gpgpu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to install NVIDIA driver and CUDA on Ubuntu 23.10</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-cuda-on-ubuntu-23-10/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 07:05:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-cuda-on-ubuntu-23-10/</guid><description>In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through the process of installing proper NVIDIA drivers and CUDA on Ubuntu 23.10.
Scenario Let&amp;rsquo;s first understand the situation you might be facing:
You own an NVIDIA GPU and need to install CUDA. You&amp;rsquo;re facing issues with missing NVIDIA drivers. The additional driver option in Ubuntu is displaying errors like pc-client-error-quark. Figure: The Additional Drivers interface may display errors for all available NVIDIA drivers (both proprietary and open).</description></item><item><title>Introduction to SYCL and DPC&#43;&#43;</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/sycl-docker-interactive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 08:01:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/sycl-docker-interactive/</guid><description>SYCL is an open industry standard, not a programming language itself, developed by the Khronos Group to facilitate data parallelism in C++ for heterogeneous computing systems. This means you can write single-source C++ code that utilizes the power of various processors like CPUs, GPUs, and FPGAs in a single program. This improves code maintainability and portability across different hardware platforms.
Core characteristics of SYCL:
Single-source programming: Write code once and target diverse hardware architectures without rewriting for each device.</description></item><item><title>cuDF vs Pandas dataframe performance comparison</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/cudf-vs-df/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 08:01:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/cudf-vs-df/</guid><description>cuDF is a Python GPU DataFrame library with similar functionalities to Pandas DataFrame. It can be used for loading, joining, aggregating, filtering, and manipulating large datasets leveraging GPU programming models. cuDF provides a pandas-like API, so the developers or data scientists do not need to dive deeper into the CUDA programming model. It is a part of the Rapids suite that utilizes the NVIDIA CUDA® programming model to expose high bandwidth memory speed and GPU parallelism.</description></item></channel></rss>