<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>docker on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</title><link>https://arshovon.com/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in docker on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 10:17:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arshovon.com/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install Soufflé on Ubuntu using Docker</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-souffl%C3%A9-on-ubuntu-docker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 10:17:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-souffl%C3%A9-on-ubuntu-docker/</guid><description>What is Soufflé? Soufflé1 is an open source &amp;ldquo;state of the art&amp;rdquo; Datalog engine that uses OpenMP for parallelization in C++. It provides a compiler to translate Datalog programs into efficient C++ code, enabling Soufflé to handle large datasets while maintaining fast execution speeds. Soufflé also offers an interpreter for quick testing and debugging of Datalog programs. In addition to its core functionality, Soufflé offers several advanced features2, including:</description></item><item><title>Install deal.II on Ubuntu using Docker</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-dealii-on-ubuntu-docker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 10:17:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-dealii-on-ubuntu-docker/</guid><description>What is deal.II? deal.II1 is an open source software library written in C++ for solving partial differential equations (PDEs) using the finite element method (FEM). It provides a comprehensive set of tools for solving complex PDEs arising in various fields, including fluid dynamics, solid mechanics, electromagnetics, and quantum mechanics. It is designed to be flexible, efficient, and scalable, supporting parallel computing on a wide range of architectures. The library provides a high-level interface for generating meshes, defining finite element spaces, assembling and solving linear systems, and post-processing and visualizing solutions.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to SYCL and DPC&#43;&#43;</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/sycl-docker-interactive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 08:01:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/sycl-docker-interactive/</guid><description>SYCL is an open industry standard, not a programming language itself, developed by the Khronos Group to facilitate data parallelism in C++ for heterogeneous computing systems. This means you can write single-source C++ code that utilizes the power of various processors like CPUs, GPUs, and FPGAs in a single program. This improves code maintainability and portability across different hardware platforms.
Core characteristics of SYCL:
Single-source programming: Write code once and target diverse hardware architectures without rewriting for each device.</description></item><item><title>Install Gatsby on Ubuntu 20.04</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-gatsby-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 05:05:11 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-gatsby-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>What is Gatsby? Gatsby is a React based build time static site generator that uses Webpack and GraphQL. It makes easy to work with data in React apps. It contains GraphQL data layer. During build time Gatsby fetches all the data, renders the entire website into static HTML, CSS, JS files with the data available at that time. As it generates the static files, Gatsby applications can be deployed in anywhere.</description></item><item><title>Run YesWorkflow Docker Image on Ubuntu 20.04</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/yesworkflow-docker-run/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 15:05:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/yesworkflow-docker-run/</guid><description>YesWorkflow YesWorkflow is a modeling and provenance management tool for scripting languages.
Run Docker image of YesWorkflow Download YesWorkflow repository from: https://github.com/yesworkflow-org/yw-docker Open a terminal in yw-cli directory. Create a folder named codes inside current directory. Create a file example.py with the following content in the codes directory:
import netCDF4 import numpy as np from netCDF4 import ma import matplotlib.pyplot as plt from matplotlib.backends.backend_pdf import PdfPages # @BEGIN main # @PARAM db_pth # @PARAM fmodel # @IN input_mask_file @URI file:{db_pth}/land_water_mask/LandWaterMask_Global_CRUNCEP.</description></item><item><title>Install Docker on Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 07:05:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>Environment Operating System : Raspbian GNU/Linux 9 (stretch) Model : Raspberry Pi 2 (Model B) Docker Installation Procedure on Raspberry Pi The following steps showed the step by step installation guideline.
Raspian Information Check the model of the Raspberry Pi:
cat /proc/device-tree/model It confirms that I have a Raspberry Pi 2 (Model B)
Raspberry Pi 2 Model B Rev 1.1 Check the Operating System (OS) of the Raspberry Pi:</description></item><item><title>Develop Flask Application using Docker and Bootstrap Templates</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/develop-flask-app-using-docker-and-bootstrap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 07:05:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/develop-flask-app-using-docker-and-bootstrap/</guid><description>Prerequisite Docker Engine should be installed in local machine. Instructions on installing Docker Engine on Ubuntu can be found in this tutorial: Install Docker on Ubuntu 18.04
Environment Operating System : Ubuntu 18.04 LTS (64-bit) Processor : Intel® Core™ i7-8750H CPU @ 2.20GHz × 12 Memory : 15.3 GiB Code Repository All codes used in this tutorial can be found in this Github repository: https://github.</description></item><item><title>Install Docker Compose on Ubuntu 18.04</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-compose-on-ubuntu-18-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 09:05:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-compose-on-ubuntu-18-04/</guid><description>What is Docker Compose? Compose is a tool for defining and running complex applications with Docker. With Compose, you define a multi-container application in a single file, then spin your application up in a single command which does everything that needs to be done to get it running.
Compose uses a YML\YAML file to configure application&amp;rsquo;s services. Then, with a single command, all the services can be started or stopped from the configuration.</description></item><item><title>Install Docker on Ubuntu 22.10</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-ubuntu-22-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 07:05:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-ubuntu-22-10/</guid><description>Why Docker? Docker is a tool for running application in an isolated environment.
Some reasons you might want to use Docker:
Same environment: Same environment in developers machines and production servers. Acts the same. Sandbox projects: Eliminates the risk of getting conflicts while working on different projects on same machine. Easy working without setup hassle: Start working directly on others projects without setting all of the environments.</description></item></channel></rss>