<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>deployment on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</title><link>https://arshovon.com/categories/deployment/</link><description>Recent content in deployment on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 11:05:42 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arshovon.com/categories/deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup Odoo with Docker Compose</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/setup-odoo-with-docker-compose/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 11:05:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/setup-odoo-with-docker-compose/</guid><description>What is Odoo? Odoo is one of the most popular business management software which provides features like CRM, e-commerce, billing, accounting, manufacturing, warehouse, project management, and inventory management in a single application. It provides an Enterprise edition and a Community edition which is LGPLv3 open source version. The source code for the framework and core ERP modules is curated by the Belgium-based Odoo S.A. Odoo was released on February 2005 and is written in Python, JavaScript and XML.</description></item><item><title>Develop Flask Application using Docker and Bootstrap Templates</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/develop-flask-app-using-docker-and-bootstrap/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 07:05:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/develop-flask-app-using-docker-and-bootstrap/</guid><description>Prerequisite Docker Engine should be installed in local machine. Instructions on installing Docker Engine on Ubuntu can be found in this tutorial: Install Docker on Ubuntu 18.04
Environment Operating System : Ubuntu 18.04 LTS (64-bit) Processor : Intel® Core™ i7-8750H CPU @ 2.20GHz × 12 Memory : 15.3 GiB Code Repository All codes used in this tutorial can be found in this Github repository: https://github.</description></item><item><title>Install Docker Compose on Ubuntu 18.04</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-compose-on-ubuntu-18-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 09:05:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-compose-on-ubuntu-18-04/</guid><description>What is Docker Compose? Compose is a tool for defining and running complex applications with Docker. With Compose, you define a multi-container application in a single file, then spin your application up in a single command which does everything that needs to be done to get it running.
Compose uses a YML\YAML file to configure application&amp;rsquo;s services. Then, with a single command, all the services can be started or stopped from the configuration.</description></item><item><title>Install Docker on Ubuntu 18.04</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-ubuntu-18-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 07:05:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-ubuntu-18-04/</guid><description>Why Docker? Docker is a tool for running application in an isolated environment.
Some reasons you might want to use Docker:
Same environment: Same environment in developers machines and production servers. Acts the same. Sandbox projects: Eliminates the risk of getting conflicts while working on different projects on same machine. Easy working without setup hassle: Start working directly on others projects without setting all of the environments.</description></item></channel></rss>