<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</title>
    <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 22:31:21 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://arshovon.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Create custom email address and attach with Gmail</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/custom-email-with-gmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 13:14:12 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/custom-email-with-gmail/</guid>
      <description>Scenario  I have a Gmail address (e.g.: free@gmail.com) I have a domain (e.g.: example.com) I want to make a custom email address with own domain (e.g.: hello@example.com) I want to receive all the emails sent to custom email address in my Gmail (e.g.: hello@example.com -&amp;gt; free@gmail.com) I want to send email from custom email address while sending emails from my Gmail (e.g.: select hello@example.com as sender from free@gmail.com)  Solution Set up email forwarding The first step is to set up email forwarding in the domain management dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Docker on Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 07:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>Environment   Operating System : Raspbian GNU/Linux 9 (stretch)  Model : Raspberry Pi 2 (Model B)  Docker Installation Procedure on Raspberry Pi The following steps showed the step by step installation guideline.
Raspian Information  Check the model of the Raspberry Pi:
cat /proc/device-tree/model  It confirms that I have a Raspberry Pi 2 (Model B)
Raspberry Pi 2 Model B Rev 1.1  Check the Operating System (OS) of the Raspberry Pi:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorting Algorithm Comparisons</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/sorting-algorithm-comparisons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 02:06:33 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/sorting-algorithm-comparisons/</guid>
      <description>Sorting Algorithm Comparisons Table   Criteria Bubble Selection Insertion Merge Quick Counting Timsort     Technique Brute force Brute force Brute force Divide-and-conquer Divide-and-conquer Non comparison Hybrid   Worst Time O(n2) O(n2) O(n2) O(nlgn) O(n2) O(k+n) O(nlgn)   Average Time Θ(n2) Θ(n2) Θ(n2) Θ(nlgn) Θ(nlgn) Θ(k+n) Θ(nlgn)   Best Time Ω(n) Ω(n2) Ω(n) Ω(nlgn) Ω(nlgn) Ω(k+n) Ω(n)   Space O(1) O(1) O(1) O(n) O(n) O(k+n) O(n)   Stable Yes No Yes Yes No Yes Yes   In-place Yes Yes Yes No Yes No    Online No No Yes No No No No   Adaptive Yes No Yes No Yes No Yes   Suitable for Sorted list  Almost sorted list List with unknown order  0&amp;lt;=A[i]&amp;lt;=k     Criteria Explanation  Technique: Methodology of the sorting algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insertion Sort</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/insertion-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 02:06:33 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/insertion-sort/</guid>
      <description>Characteristics Simple implementation Insertion sort can be implemented easily with less lines of code. It is quite efficient for small data sets. Though it has same complexity than other quadratic sorting algorithms like selection sort or bubble sort, insertion sort is more efficient.
Adaptive Insertion sort is adaptive. If the input data set is already sorted, the number of steps are reduced.
Online Insertion sort works on the data as it receives it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting Sort</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/counting-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 11:07:32 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/counting-sort/</guid>
      <description>Characteristics Non negative integers with a known maximum value Counting sort can be applied if the input numbers are in the set {0, 1, .. ,k}, a set of non negative integers with a maximum value k.
No comparisons between elements There are no comparisons between input elements that take place in counting sort. It uses array indexing to determine the relative order of the input numbers. It identifies the relative positions of each input element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to django CMS</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/introduction-to-django-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:01:44 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/introduction-to-django-cms/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to django CMS In this article we will:
 Learn about django CMS Analyze its features Setup an application with django CMS with full installation guidelines  About django CMS django CMS is an open source enterprise content management system based on the Django framework.
django CMS is voted Best Open Source CMS in 2015. [Announcing the 2015 Winner for Best Open Source CMS]
django CMS&amp;rsquo;s lightweight core enables integrating it with other software with ease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use SSH to logging into Raspberry Pi without Password</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/logging-to-raspberry-pi-without-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 08:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/logging-to-raspberry-pi-without-password/</guid>
      <description>Scenario We can login into remote Raspberry Pi using ssh command:
ssh -p PORT USER@IP password: RASPBERRY_PASSWORD  As it can be seen, we require to input the Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s password each time to establish SSH connection.
Solution: Add local machine&amp;rsquo;s SSH key to Raspberry Pi for password less SSH connection To resolve the scenario, we need to add our local machine&amp;rsquo;s SSH key to the Raspberry Pi.
 Check if you have SSH key in local machine using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Odoo with Docker Compose</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/setup-odoo-with-docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 11:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/setup-odoo-with-docker-compose/</guid>
      <description>What is Odoo? Odoo is one of the most popular business management software which provides features like CRM, e-commerce, billing, accounting, manufacturing, warehouse, project management, and inventory management in a single application. It provides an Enterprise edition and a Community edition which is LGPLv3 open source version. The source code for the framework and core ERP modules is curated by the Belgium-based Odoo S.A. Odoo was released on February 2005 and is written in Python, JavaScript and XML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop Flask Application using Docker and Bootstrap Templates</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/develop-flask-app-using-docker-and-bootstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 07:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/develop-flask-app-using-docker-and-bootstrap/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisite Docker Engine should be installed in local machine. Instructions on installing Docker Engine on Ubuntu can be found in this tutorial: Install Docker on Ubuntu 18.04
Environment   Operating System : Ubuntu 18.04 LTS (64-bit)  Processor : Intel® Core™ i7-8750H CPU @ 2.20GHz × 12  Memory : 15.3 GiB  Code Repository All codes used in this tutorial can be found in this Github repository: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Docker Compose on Ubuntu 18.04</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-compose-on-ubuntu-18-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 09:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-compose-on-ubuntu-18-04/</guid>
      <description>What is Docker Compose? Compose is a tool for defining and running complex applications with Docker. With Compose, you define a multi-container application in a single file, then spin your application up in a single command which does everything that needs to be done to get it running.
Compose uses a YML\YAML file to configure application&amp;rsquo;s services. Then, with a single command, all the services can be started or stopped from the configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Docker on Ubuntu 18.04</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-ubuntu-18-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 07:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-docker-on-ubuntu-18-04/</guid>
      <description>Why Docker? Docker is a tool for running application in an isolated environment.
Some reasons you might want to use Docker:
  Same environment:  Same environment in developers machines and production servers. Acts the same.  Sandbox projects:  Eliminates the risk of getting conflicts while working on different projects on same machine.  Easy working without setup hassle:  Start working directly on others projects without setting all of the environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Java Program in Ubuntu 18.04</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/run-java-program-ubuntu-18-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 15:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/run-java-program-ubuntu-18-04/</guid>
      <description>Run Java Program in Ubuntu 18.04. The program will be run using Oracle&#39;s OpenJDK JDK 8.
 Check if Java Runtime Environment(JRE) is installed in machine:
java -version  If JRE is installed it will show the version information similar to following:
openjdk 11.0.5 2019-10-15 OpenJDK Runtime Environment (build 11.0.5+10-post-Ubuntu-0ubuntu1.118.04) OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM (build 11.0.5+10-post-Ubuntu-0ubuntu1.118.04, mixed mode)  If you do not have installed JRE, install JRE using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Django Custom Management Command</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/django-custom-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 13:14:12 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/django-custom-command/</guid>
      <description>When developing application using Django framework, we extensively use various Django commands. Few common Django commands we use regularly are:
 python manage.py runserver python manage.py makemigrations python manage.py migrate  These commands are built in and lies within Django itself.
We can also write custom Django admin command. Today I will show an example of wrinting custom Django admin command.
These custom admin commands can be invoked using manage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic features of Saas with example</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/saas-basic-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 16:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/saas-basic-features/</guid>
      <description>Sass(Syntactically Awesome Style Sheets) is the most mature, stable, and powerful professional grade CSS extension language in the world.
Features  CSS Compatible: Sass is completely compatible with all versions of CSS. Mature: Sass has been actively supported for about 12 years by its loving Core Team. Frameworks: Popular frameworks built with Sass -&amp;gt; Compass, Bourbon, and Susy. Nesting: HTML elements are nested. But CSS elements are not nested by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install CLI Tools Ubuntu 18.04</title>
      <link>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-cli-tools-ubuntu-18-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 15:05:42 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/install-cli-tools-ubuntu-18-04/</guid>
      <description>Install basic development CLI tools in Ubuntu 18.04. It includes:
 oh-my-zsh idle venv git tree  Install Git in Ubuntu 18.04 LTS  Install Git:
sudo apt install git  Add global configuration for Git user:
git config --global user.email &amp;quot;you@example.com&amp;quot; git config --global user.name &amp;quot;Your Name&amp;quot;  Add SSH. Details can be found in this gist
  Install Oh My Zsh in Ubuntu 18.04 LTS  Install Zsh:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>