<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SQL on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</title><link>https://arshovon.com/tags/sql/</link><description>Recent content in SQL on Ahmedur Rahman Shovon</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 15:27:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arshovon.com/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recursive queries in SQL and Datalog</title><link>https://arshovon.com/blog/recursive-queries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 10:13:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://arshovon.com/blog/recursive-queries/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recursive queries are a type of database query that involves recursively traversing and querying hierarchical or self-referential data structures.
They are particularly useful for querying data that has a nested or hierarchical representation.
Recursive queries enable developers to navigate and process these complex data structures by iteratively applying a set of rules or conditions until a termination criterion is met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="recursive-queries-in-sql"&gt;Recursive queries in SQL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recursive queries were introduced as part of the SQL:1999 standard which is known as SQL3, a major revision to the SQL language&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
Prior to SQL3, SQL lacked built-in support for querying hierarchical or recursive data structures like organizational charts, bill-of-materials data, and network/graph data.
The introduction of recursive queries in SQL3 empowered developers to effectively query hierarchical or self-referential data structures.
Unlike traditional SQL queries that operate on a static set of rows, recursive queries enable traversal and manipulation of hierarchical data structures by iteratively executing an anchor and recursive member.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>